<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-06-29T02:25:20+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Anirudh Gautam</title><entry><title type="html">Beyond the Classroom</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/beyond-the-classroom/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beyond the Classroom" /><published>2024-06-29T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2024-06-29T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/beyond-the-classroom</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/beyond-the-classroom/">&lt;figure style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/iiitm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of trading strategy written on tablet&quot; /&gt; 
    
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never thought much about college when I was younger. It was just something you were supposed to do after high school. But those years were a bigger deal than I realized at the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, those years were a series of small experiments. Some failed, others succeeded in ways I never anticipated. Each one taught me something, not just about the subject at hand, but about myself and the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t a guide on how to “do” college right. If my experience taught me anything, it’s that there’s no one right way. Instead, this is a collection of observations and lessons learned, offered in the hope that they might be useful to someone who’s about to start this journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-fresh-start&quot;&gt;The Fresh Start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember that shy kid from high school? Well, in college, that could become history. College offers a rare opportunity to reset your personal narrative. Nobody knows if you were the class clown, the wallflower, or the overachiever back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I saw classmates who’d always been labeled as “geeks” discover a passion for theater. Others who’d never raised their hand in school became vocal participants in classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This change isn’t something that just happens to you; it’s something you actively participate in. Every class you choose, every club you join, every late-night conversation you engage in – they’re all part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t about becoming a whole new person, though. It’s more like… becoming more you. You’re not carrying all that baggage from school anymore, you’re free to explore who you really are – or who you want to become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;explore&quot;&gt;“Explore”&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Make sure to explore!” This was the most common advice I got from seniors.
It’s the advice equivalent of being told to “have fun” at a party where you don’t know anyone. Well-intentioned, but frustratingly vague.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, exploration became synonymous with stepping into the discomfort zone. It meant following my curiosity down unexpected rabbit holes, going beyond my declared major, and learning to say “yes” to new experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, I realize that the vagueness of the “explore” advice was its strength. There was no one right way to do it. My path of exploration was uniquely mine, shaped by my interests, fears, and random chances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to now see how it all fits together. But when you’re in the middle of it, it often feels like you’re just stumbling around. Make peace with it. That stumbling is how you find the interesting stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-are-you-in-college&quot;&gt;Why are you in college?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months into college, you might start wondering why you’re there. You’re learning a ton on your own — YouTube, side projects, just reading stuff. So what’s the point of college, really?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t find the answer to this in my first year, but over time, I realized that I’m paying for the opportunity to be among a crowd of really smart people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not obvious at first how much this matters. But it adds up. Every internship I got, every little freelance job, every cool opportunity - they all came from people I met at college. Sometimes it was a friend putting in a good word, or just chatting with a senior, or an alum giving me advice. These little things that seemed so small at the time? They ended up shaping my whole college experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The most valuable lessons often happen outside the lecture hall. Your job is to show up and be open to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-losing-interest&quot;&gt;Not Losing Interest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most surprising things about my first year wasn’t the hectic coursework or the newfound independence. It was watching a good chunk of my classmates lose interest in programming before we’d even scratched the surface because their first introduction to it was making calculators in C in college classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s something soul-crushing about spending hours debugging semicolons, pointers, or struggling to understand abstract concepts when all you want to do is create something meaningful. It’s far from the experience many of us imagined when we signed up for Computer Science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losing interest early isn’t always about being uninterested in the subject. Sometimes, it’s about not finding the right way to engage with it. And unfortunately, that realization often comes too late. Modern programming is incredibly diverse. It can be creative, analytical, or a blend of both. It can involve building beautiful interfaces or solving complex algorithmic puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re in that first year, seek out coding projects that excite you. Look beyond your coursework to see how programming is being used in fields that interest you. Join coding clubs or hackathons where you can work on more engaging projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-everything-youre-doing-needs-to-make-sense&quot;&gt;Not everything you’re doing needs to make sense&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a certain pressure in college to have it all figured out. To have a clear plan, a defined path. While this has its merits, it shouldn’t come at the cost of experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my second year of college, a few friends and I started day trading. It was amidst the global lockdowns and virtual classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would join meets, backtest strategies, and share observations. After months of doing this, we finally started making sense of a few things and developed some strategies that we thought could work. We did the math and quickly realized that with the capital we had, effective risk management wasn’t possible and our chances of success were about as good as getting heads on a coin toss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of abandoning ship, we pivoted. Our new goal became finding ways to earn money to build the capital we needed. This shift led us to freelancing, which, ironically, ended up being far more lucrative than our trading ambitions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years later, some of us are into algo trading, while others have found substantial success continuing with freelancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were naive enough to think we could compete against seasoned quant teams, but that naivety led us to valuable experiences in unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, while it’s good to have a plan, don’t let it constrain you. Leave room for the illogical, the experimental, the things that don’t quite make sense. You never know where they might lead you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/stockstrategy.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Image of trading strategy written on tablet&quot; style=&quot;width: 400px; height: 300px;&quot; /&gt; 
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Things that made a lot of sense to us back then.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-some-side-hustle&quot;&gt;Do some side hustle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most transformative experiences you can have in college isn’t listed in any course catalog: making your own money. It’s not about getting rich quick.
It’s about the shift in mindset that occurs when you start earning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re no longer solely dependent on your parents or financial aid for every expense. Want to buy a domain name for that side project? Host a website? Attend a conference? Pay for that mentorship? You can make these decisions independently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having some financial independence changes how you interact with the world. You become more proactive, more willing to take calculated risks. You begin to understand the value of your time and skills in a way that textbooks can’t teach.
You begin to understand why everybody is always talking about opportunity costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just don’t forget to balance it with your studies. After all, you’re still in college to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. Ignore if you’re ultra rich&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;is-your-cgpa-important&quot;&gt;Is your CGPA important?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A high CGPA might not be necessary for every career path, but it certainly makes life easier in college.
With a good CGPA, you get priority in mentor selections for projects, more flexibility in choosing courses, better on-campus shortlisting opportunities and perhaps most importantly it often buys you goodwill with faculty and administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into trouble or need an exception made, a history of good performance can tip the scales in your favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be surprised if your CGPA is asked before your name if you ever run into any trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key is finding a CGPA balance that keeps opportunities available without sacrificing your overall college experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;internships&quot;&gt;Internships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internships have this funny way of either confirming your career path or throwing it into complete disarray. That frontend internship might make you realize you actually hate doing designs. Or that internship at a startup might inspire you to have your own startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went into my first internship convinced I wanted to be a Data scientist. Two months later, I was fascinated by Backend engineering. It was confusing and a little scary, but ultimately, it helped me find a career path I’m truly passionate about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internships are your chance to test-drive a career, to make mistakes in a (somewhat) safe environment, and to start building the network that will support you throughout your professional life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They’re also a great reality check. You might discover that your dream job isn’t so dreamy after all. Or you might stumble into a field you never considered and fall in love with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, you’ll come out of it with new skills, new connections, and probably a few good stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-competition-explosion&quot;&gt;The Competition Explosion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internships hunting used to be much simpler. Now, things have changed quite a lot. The competition for internships has increased tenfold, and the process has become much more intense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These days, you’ll find dedicated groups on every social media platform where internship opportunities are posted. The moment a new opening appears, hundreds of students rush to apply. It’s incredibly fast-paced and overwhelming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What used to be a manageable number of applicants for each position has turned into a flood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting a referral also used to be a big deal. Now? It’s almost become too easy. Reach out to company employees on LinkedIn with a decent profile, and – referral acquired. It’s great that it’s more accessible, but when everyone’s special, no one is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This increased competition means you need to be quicker, more prepared, and more strategic in your approach. It’s not just about finding opportunities anymore - it’s about standing out in a very crowded field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;finding-your-own-alpha&quot;&gt;Finding Your Own Alpha&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to go off the beaten path. Maybe it’s reaching out directly to the CEO of a startup on Twitter. Perhaps it’s creating a project that solves a problem for a company you want to work for. Or it could be leveraging your unique background or network in a way no one else has thought of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I landed my internship at Google through a cold email. It was a shot in the dark, but it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point is, find your own “alpha” – do something that sets you apart from the crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding internship or a job is easily going to be the most hectic time of your college. Sending 10s of requests every day, filling those long forms, always studying to be interview ready, juggling classes and academic work. It might even remind you of your JEE days. The pressure is real, and the competition is fierce and you’ll hear “No” a lot but it only takes one yes to change the trajectory of your career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-hidden-curriculum&quot;&gt;The Hidden Curriculum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout all of this, there’s a hidden curriculum at work. It’s not listed anywhere, but it’s arguably more important than any class you’ll take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You learn how to learn. How to think critically. How to communicate with a wide range of people. How to manage your time, adapt to new environments, balance multiple responsibilities, deal with stress and uncertainty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These might not be listed on my transcript, but in many ways, they’re the most practical things I’ll take away from my college years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;College also teaches you that time is relative. One minute in a boring lecture feels like an hour, while one hour before a deadline feels like a nanosecond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-up&quot;&gt;Wrapping Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;College wasn’t exactly what I expected. It was harder in some ways and easier in others. I learned things I never thought I’d care about. I made friends I’ll keep for life, and got torn apart from people I thought would always be there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s tempting to see college as a means to an end - a step towards a career, a degree, a future salary. But a lot of value lies in the journey itself. In the people you meet, the ideas you encounter, the habits you form, and the person you slowly become.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This journey wasn’t a straight line, and it shouldn’t be. Embrace those detours. They’re often where the most interesting discoveries happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You enter college as a rough draft of yourself. That first year is when you really start the editing process. And like any good edit, it involves a lot of crossing out, rewriting, and moments where you stare blankly at the page wondering what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s the beauty of it. You’re the author now. The story is yours to write.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>anirudh</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Experience" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/anirudh.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/anirudh.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Summer Internship with Google: The Good, The Googly, and The Unforgettable!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/google-internship/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Summer Internship with Google: The Good, The Googly, and The Unforgettable!" /><published>2023-10-02T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2023-10-02T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/google-internship</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/google-internship/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/enterance.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This summer, I had the opportunity to intern at Google. In this blog, I’ll share a recount of my experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A heads-up: I won’t be covering the interview process, so if that’s what you’re keen on, you might want to look elsewhere. With that said, let’s delve into my Google journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-the-google-offer&quot;&gt;Getting the Google Offer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a seemingly ordinary September 14th last year, I committed the timeless ritual of college students worldwide: missing that darn 9am class. Yup, 10 o’clock rolled around, and there I was, cocooned in my blankets, blissfully unaware. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
A week had passed since my interviews, and I was gearing up to nudge my recruiter with a follow-up email. But as I peeked at my tab, a new message caught my eye: “Congratulations on your Google summer internship offer!”. My brain went from 0 to 100, from “Did I just dream that?” to “Wait, this is real!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news spread like wildfire - family, friends, that neighbor I only nod at (he had to know!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the universe decided I needed a crash course in patience. A 9-month-long wait, if you will, before I join Google. But hey, all good things happen to those who wait (and snooze)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-impressions-of-the-google-bangalore-office-the-colors-the-people-the-food&quot;&gt;First impressions of the Google Bangalore office: The colors! The people! The food!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went in with some fairly high expectations, built on hours of binge-watching “Day in a life of a Google engineer” videos. But Google exceeded all of them in reality!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has four offices in Bangalore. I landed in Google’s RMZ office. Even though it’s smaller in size, believe me, it makes a big impression! And, let’s just say, the “Which is the best Google office?” debate among us interns is more heated than “tabs vs. spaces” among coders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rmz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rmz Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though our work setup was hybrid, requiring only three days a week in the office and the rest from home, only few could resist the temptation to head into the office daily.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/food.png&quot; alt=&quot;Food Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “office” never truly felt like one. At first, I assumed this fresh vibe was because everything was new to us. But, interestingly, that buzz persisted, right up until my final intern day. It was an environment like no other!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-team&quot;&gt;The Team&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was part of a team within Google’s search division.&lt;br /&gt;
Upon sharing this with my mom, she candidly asked, “Can you see what I’m searching for on Google?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little did she know that even getting printer access as an intern required director-level sign-off. My initial two weeks were mostly spent with my host trying to get all the necessary permissions and solve access issues for my project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All kidding aside, Google’s commitment to privacy is unparalleled. Their stringent access controls reaffirm my trust as a frequent user of Google apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never felt more confident about the security of my data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-project&quot;&gt;The Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nature of a project an intern would get often relied heavily on the specific team they were paired with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there were a few consistent aspects across the board:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The project setup was relatively autonomous. The primary stakeholders typically consists of an intern, the Host (Manager), and the Cohost (Buddy).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The scope of the project was decided in a manner that ensured tangible results by the end of the internship period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team was responsible for deploying a critical component (let’s call it ‘groot’) of Google Search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem - If a developer who contributed to Groot wanted to see if their work was in the production environment, they had a tool. But if they wanted to know WHEN it would reach production, that’s where things got tough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My task was to build a new internal tool to help developers get an estimate on when their change will reach production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, it wasn’t all smooth sailing. Think of it as trying to predict when your online order will arrive, but the delivery process has loads of random stops. So, lots of thinking and re-thinking!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best bit? My &lt;a href=&quot;https://in.linkedin.com/in/monica-sai-kambala&quot;&gt;Host&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://in.linkedin.com/in/ashrut22&quot;&gt;Cohost&lt;/a&gt; were the real MVPs. They had my back, making everything fun and giving me the captain’s hat for our project journey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beyond-the-desk&quot;&gt;Beyond the Desk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My time at Google was so much more than just about work. From intern getaways to team retreats, the experience was brimming with opportunities for fun and bonding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One particular adventure stood out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teaming up with four fellow interns, we collaborated with the Talent Engagement team to create a video that would showcase a day in the life of a Google intern.&lt;br /&gt;
Our mission? To capture those unscripted moments that make internships memorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I roped in several other interns to help document our escapades around the office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outcome? A collection of over 30 clips! 90% of them were just us laughing, joking, and simply enjoying our time together.
We passed the remaining ones to the Talent Engagement team, and voilà! Here’s the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; justify-content: center; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-permalink=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/reel/CuhkfI9se73/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;14&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:540px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:16px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/reel/CuhkfI9se73/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 19% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;&quot;&gt;&lt;svg width=&quot;50px&quot; height=&quot;50px&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 60 60&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; xmlns=&quot;https://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot; xmlns:xlink=&quot;https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink&quot;&gt;&lt;g stroke=&quot;none&quot; stroke-width=&quot;1&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot;&gt;&lt;g transform=&quot;translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)&quot; fill=&quot;#000000&quot;&gt;&lt;g&gt;&lt;path d=&quot;M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/g&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding-top: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;&quot;&gt;View this post on Instagram&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding: 12.5% 0;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;&quot;&gt;&lt;div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: 8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;margin-left: auto;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center; margin-bottom: 24px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 224px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 144px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/reel/CuhkfI9se73/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;amp;utm_campaign=loading&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A post shared by Google Students (@googlestudents)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt; &lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//www.instagram.com/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bangalore-adventures&quot;&gt;Bangalore Adventures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be remiss not to mention Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the three months I was there, Bangalore consistently surprised me. From its unpredictable(although good) weather to cab bookings taking eternity, I experienced it all, yet, in spite of its challenges, there was never a dull moment over the weekends. I tried a few activities like Go-karting, shooting for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From peaceful places like Cubbon Park and the ISKCON Temple to vibrant nightclubs, Bangalore has something for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/map.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Map Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Going on a PG hunt in Bangalore be like: Bookmarking the entire city!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-big-presentation&quot;&gt;The Big Presentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the internship, there’s a mid-point evaluation, which for me came in the 6th week (given my internship was 12 weeks long).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s also a final evaluation in the 11th week, followed by a presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my second last day at work, it was time for my internship presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This presentation is an opportunity to showcase your work not just to your immediate team, but also to related teams within the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My project went live just a week prior. I spent the following week polishing up minor details and preparing for this showcase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the diverse audience, ranging from L3 to L8 levels and from various teams, planning the presentation’s content was a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my delight, the presentation went off without a hitch. The compliments I received afterward are still fresh in my memory, and they made me feel on top of the world. And as a cherry on top, my team threw me a surprise farewell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/farewell.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Food Image&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;figcaption class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pov: your farewell happens to fall on ethnic wear day!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you’re wondering, yes, I &lt;del&gt;(had to)&lt;/del&gt; delivered my final presentation in a kurta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;parents-first-time-at-office&quot;&gt;Parents First Time at Office&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks into the office, I decided that my parents had to see this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They visited the office on Friday of last week. I was already done with my exit formalities, presentation and we all interns were trying to enjoy that day to the fullest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took them a good 30 minutes to get comfortable in the environment. Perhaps it was the sight of people walking in their casual shorts and slippers that helped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I gave them a tour, highlighting the office’s cafe, meeting spaces, micro-kitchens, gaming zone, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/first_visit.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we concluded our exploration, the smiles on their faces seemed to capture more than just a day’s experience. In their eyes, I saw a mix of pride and amusement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their joyous expressions became the most memorable snapshot, a fitting conclusion to my internship journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wrapping-up-and-looking-ahead&quot;&gt;Wrapping Up and Looking Ahead&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on those 3 months, my growth wasn’t just technical. But beyond that, my journey was filled with fun. The people I met, from supportive teammates to incredible friends, ensured that my time there was never mundane.
Thank you Google, the search team, and all the amazing Googlers I met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/messages.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The internship chapter closes, but these memories ensure it’s a story I’ll revisit often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And oh, the Google vibe? Totally lived up to the hype!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel I’ve barely scratched the surface of all I absorbed in those 3 months. While I could pen another blog solely focused on the lessons, my intent here was to offer a genuine glimpse into my time at Google.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve made it this far, thank you for sticking around! I hope you had a worthy time reading my experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time, Anirudh.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>anirudh</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Internship" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/anirudh.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/anirudh.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>